66. The academic realism that emerged after the end of the First World War was based on an 
  interpretation of the works of which writers?
  A) Marx, Hobbes, Lenin
  B) Machiavelli, Hobbes
  C) Smith, Hawken, Rousseau
  D) Engels, Locke, Plato

67. According to the book a theory is:
  A) the same as a hypothesis
  B) never the result of analysis
  C) unlikely to satisfy the criteria for rigor
  D) a proposed explanation for an event or behavior

68. The arena with no overarching central authority above the individual collection of 
  sovereign states within which international politics takes place is known as:
  A) anarchy
  B) political community
  C) international system
  D) sovereignty

69. The Gulf War 1990-91 has been used as an example of
  A) liberal institutionalism
  B) collective security
  C) advocacy networks
  D) Wilsonian positivism

70. Which of the following is not considered a key liberal value?
  A) Tolerance
  B) Freedom
  C) Order
  D) Constitutionalism

71. What concept supposes that liberal states will not go to war with one another?
  A) Sovereign equality of states
  B) Balance of power
  C) Democratic peace thesis
  D) Republican constitutionalism







                  Page 12

