.	
. .	

. i•••• .	

.	
.	
. . .


12. Globalization might pull power away from the state, but it is also a possibility that  
globalization has what additional ability?
A) To limit the abilities of IGOs such as the UN and EU
B) To promote a global minimum wage
C) To empower local groups who want to defend their position in this global society
D) To homogenize global society
13. Some writers believe that the greatest problem with global governance is that:
A) people will gain with global governance
B) the nonstate institutions are not accountable for their actions
C) capital flows are often retrograde
D) the nonstate institutions are often no more than what Chairman Mao once called  
"paper tigers."
14. For many social scientists who study international relations, there are four kinds of  
independent variables. These are:
A) individual, personal, war, peace
B) individual, national attributes, systemic, global
C) domestic, national attributes, economics, human rights
D) systemic, global, international, world
15. Constructivist scholars tend to assert that:
A) all wars are the result of rapid system changing
B) gender-based identity politics explains policy outcomes
C) there is no single historical narrative; therefore, no single perspective holds the truth
D) peace is possible if domestic transformation happens first
16. The	
ended the Thirty Years' War.
A) Peace of Westphalia
B) Peace of Preswick
C) Peace of Weserplatte
D) Peace of Miharte
17. Article 231 of the Treaty of Versailles:
A) created the system of French and British mandates over former German colonies in  
Africa
B) placed the blame for the First World War only on Germany
C) placed the blame for the First World War only on Serbia and Austria-Hungary
D) banned Germany from having submarines and an air force
Page 3

