24. What war began the era of modern total war?
   A) British colonial wars in Africa
   B) The Cold War
   C) The First World War
   D) The Second World War

25. The Warsaw Pact was created in:
   A) 1946
   B) 1922
   C) 1965
   D) 1955

26. When Vladimir Putin took office, what became more prominent and troublesome for a 
   Russia—West strategic partnership?
   A) Market capitalism
   B) Crony capitalism
   C) Authoritarianism and nationalism
   D) Militarism and Marxism

27. According to the text, what term best describes the new class of economic actors of 
   post-communist Russia?
   A) NKVD-niks
   B) Oligarchs
   C) Globalizers
   D) Second World economists

28. Which is NOT a hypothesis for why the US went to war with Iraq?
   A) Iraq represented a serious and potentially rising threat to a critically important 
       region.
   B) The US was determined to secure direct control of Iraq's massive reserves of oil.
   C) The war was the product of social pressures arising from within the United States 
       itself.
   D) The Iraqi dictator, Saddam Hussein, was violating the humanitarian rights of the 
       Kurds.

29. Constructivism studiesforces such as ideas, norms, and rules.
   A) material
   B) ideational
   C) concrete
   D) discrete




                             Page 5

