30. Most writers who call themselves constructivists argue that make
    society—and society,- in turn, shapes our actions and words.
    A) our actions and words
    B) Marx and socialism
    C) capitalism and material items
    D) technology and production

31. For postcolonial feminists, imperialism and,other forms of power really operate at the 
    intersection of
    A) gender, race, and class
    B) globalization and capitalism
    C) health care and what Marx called "a nation of shopkeepers"
    D) war and capitalism

32. "Breadwinner" is a traditionally    role of working in the     for wages and
    providing for the economic needs of the family.
    A) masculine . . . public sphere
    B) feminine . . . private sphere
    C) nongendered ... nongovernmental sector
    D) capitalist . . . social realm

33. A realist scholar might criticize the feminist theories as:
    A) being overly rational
    B) being objectively capitalist
    C) lacking social scientific rationalism
    D) insufficiently misogynous

34. According to the text, globalization      undermine/s the global state order and
    state sovereignty.
    A) never
    B) may
    C) always
    D) must

35. The process by which a state interacts with the global system of states is called:
    A) the Delphic process
    B) the foreign policy process
    C) the goal-sorting process
    D) the rational-actor model





                                     Page 6

